<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-22T16:16:37+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio Maurits Laanbroek</title><subtitle>A technical artist specialized in procedural tools creation with 8+ years’ experience working on multiple big triple A games from Assassin greed to Farcry and assisting with development of procedural USD based pipelines from the Houdini&apos;s side. Practical problem solver and taking pride in making fast, stable and user-friendly tools.
</subtitle><author><name>Maurits Laanbroek</name></author><entry><title type="html">Lightspeed procedural pipeline</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Professional/LightCraft.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lightspeed procedural pipeline" /><published>2023-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Professional/LightCraft</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Professional/LightCraft.html"><![CDATA[<p>Lightspeed procedural pipeline utilising Usd and Nvidia Omniverse.
My work was to advise and provide feedback on the system being developed.
Looking at the Houdini and USD side but also testing and experimenting with the Blueprint interface.</p>

<p>Additional work was on the creation of the building blocks tool for the demo. Making use of the data generated by the Road system as input and outputting data for the building generator.
Making use of all the features of the pipeline and showing a potential work flow.</p>

<p>See video for more details on the pipeline.
<!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. --></p>

<div class="embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/94J3e8yTW1w" width="700" height="400" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
  </iframe>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Lightspeed studios</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="highlight" /><category term="Lightspeed" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Professional" /><category term="OpenUSD" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lightspeed procedural pipeline utilising Usd and Nvidia Omniverse. My work was to advise and provide feedback on the system being developed. Looking at the Houdini and USD side but also testing and experimenting with the Blueprint interface.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rivers {Unfinished}</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Professional/Rivers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rivers {Unfinished}" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Professional/Rivers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Professional/Rivers.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="river-and-lakes">River and lakes</h2>
<h4 id="unfinished-work">Unfinished work</h4>
<p>A tool to create rivers and lake systems using a combination of Unreal blueprints and Houdini.
All the interface work and providing fast iteration times was on the Unreal side. making use of scriptable tools, geometry blueprints and other systems. Then Houdini takes the data to generate the final results. The system builds upon a set of scriptable tools and blueprints developed by a teammate. Which handles most of the curve and anchor point interactions. But was then expanded upon to provide tool specific features.</p>

<p>Planed features where the addition of influencers. objects that locally change the base settings of a river. Giving more control to the artist.</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/lightspeed/Rivers_1.png" alt="Visual feedback" />
– <em>Unfinished state of scriptable tool interface</em></p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/lightspeed/Rivers_4.png" alt="Interface" />
– <em>Current set of river properties</em></p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/lightspeed/Rivers_3.png" alt="Node graph 1" />
– <em>Blueprint system example</em></p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/lightspeed/Rivers_2.png" alt="Node graph 2" />
– <em>Blueprint system example</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Lightspeed studios</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="highlight" /><category term="Lightspeed" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Professional" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[River and lakes Unfinished work A tool to create rivers and lake systems using a combination of Unreal blueprints and Houdini. All the interface work and providing fast iteration times was on the Unreal side. making use of scriptable tools, geometry blueprints and other systems. Then Houdini takes the data to generate the final results. The system builds upon a set of scriptable tools and blueprints developed by a teammate. Which handles most of the curve and anchor point interactions. But was then expanded upon to provide tool specific features.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anvil Pipeline core nodes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Professional/AP.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anvil Pipeline core nodes" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Professional/AP</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Professional/AP.html"><![CDATA[<p>At Ubisoft I assisted in the development of a new Anvil &lt;&gt; Houdini pipeline using USD. The
goal was to rebuild the procedural pipeline to improve performance and make use of the
USD file format. The main pipeline design was done by a larger team and the design on the
Houdini side with a smaller sub-team. My task in this was to implement the Nodes on the
Houdini side, getting and sending data according to the decided design. Throughout the
process Features were changed or added based on user feedback.</p>

<h2 id="node-specifics">Node specifics</h2>
<p>Key points for the implementation were. Stability, Performance, Maintainability, User friendly.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Maintainability in this case was to make sure other people in the future could take over
maintain the nodes, without too much head scratching. Clear node layouts per
task/cluster, descriptive naming and commenting where needed.</li>
  <li>User friendly, is simply the end user experience. Doing all the hard complex work
automatically. Some examples are:
    <ul>
      <li>Handles all of the data conversions, chancing vector orders, splitting array data
back to arrays.</li>
      <li>Extracting Tool settings and converting them to a usable mesh/data format.
Converting spline data from simple points to the correct spline type that matches
the spline shape in Engine.</li>
      <li>Mesh/Entity cleanup options for better performance. But also a consistent UI
throughout all the Core nodes. For all the import and export nodes.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Get_Entities.png" alt="Node graph" />
<img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Get_usd.png" alt="Node graph" />
– <em>Node Graphs.</em></p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Get_usd_parms.png" alt="UI" />
– <em>UI for Basic Get node.</em></p>

<h2 id="documentation">Documentation</h2>
<p>Together with the development of the nodes I kept a detailed set of Confluence pages
detailing the inner functions of each node to help future developers to maintain the nodes.
And separate Confluence pages going over all the features and user interface. In addition to
multiple beginner tutorials on how to use the new pipeline. Exporting data to Houdini,
Importing in Houdini and then exporting data back to the Engine. Each node also has
embedded help Wiki’s like normal Houdini nodes.
<img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Get_Usd_wiki.png" alt="Wiki" />
– <em>Internal help wiki for one Get node.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Ubisoft Mtl</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="highlight" /><category term="Ubisoft" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Professional" /><category term="USD" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Ubisoft I assisted in the development of a new Anvil &lt;&gt; Houdini pipeline using USD. The goal was to rebuild the procedural pipeline to improve performance and make use of the USD file format. The main pipeline design was done by a larger team and the design on the Houdini side with a smaller sub-team. My task in this was to implement the Nodes on the Houdini side, getting and sending data according to the decided design. Throughout the process Features were changed or added based on user feedback.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">City walls</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Professional/CityWall.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="City walls" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Professional/CityWall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Professional/CityWall.html"><![CDATA[<p>A Simple looking but slightly complex tool. The system takes in premade wall modules of different sizes, slopes and bend direction and angles on top having to handle towers and gates placement Either automatically when intersecting with roads or at an given interval in case of the towers.
The main difficulty lies in taking a drawn curve created by an Artist and converting it to a spline with a limited number of predefined angles and segment lengths. On top of following any number of other contains. Like snaping to terrain without gaps, placing towers at a predefined interval.</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/City_wall_1.jpg" alt="Final result" />
– <em>Final result</em></p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/City_wall_3.jpg" alt="Example wall 1" />
– <em>Example of input curve</em>
<img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/City_wall_4.jpg" alt="Example wall 2" />
– <em>Example of resulting wall</em></p>

<p>With limits on slopes, there are situations where the wall cannot follow the terrain or the spline. In these cases a warning mesh is returned to show artist that a section needs some adjustment.
<img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/City_wall_5.jpg" alt="Slope limit" /></p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/City_wall_2.png" alt="Wall Node snippet" />– <em>Node snippet of tool: The screen shot was takin without any connection to engine data so parts return errors.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Ubisoft Mtl</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="highlight" /><category term="Ubisoft" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Professional" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Simple looking but slightly complex tool. The system takes in premade wall modules of different sizes, slopes and bend direction and angles on top having to handle towers and gates placement Either automatically when intersecting with roads or at an given interval in case of the towers. The main difficulty lies in taking a drawn curve created by an Artist and converting it to a spline with a limited number of predefined angles and segment lengths. On top of following any number of other contains. Like snaping to terrain without gaps, placing towers at a predefined interval.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cliff generation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Professional/CliffGeneration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cliff generation" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Professional/CliffGeneration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Professional/CliffGeneration.html"><![CDATA[<p>Automatically place cliff and rocks on steep terrain areas based on user defined cliff sets. Making sure they don’t trap players but also look nice. This is followed by blending the terrain with the procedural and manual placed rocks for a better transition between terrain and rocks.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Some constraints were to avoid roads and rivers.</li>
  <li>Follow the sloped area.</li>
  <li>Blend terrain with rocks for smooth transition</li>
  <li>Only rotate along the vertical axis for game play.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/CLiffs_jeryce-dianingana-09.jpg" alt="Stiching" />
– <em>Terrain blending in to cliffs with stitching. Img By Jeryce Dianingana</em>
<img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Cliffs_2.jpg" alt="Cliff" />
– <em>World example of generated cliffs</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Ubisoft Mtl</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="Ubisoft" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Professional" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automatically place cliff and rocks on steep terrain areas based on user defined cliff sets. Making sure they don’t trap players but also look nice. This is followed by blending the terrain with the procedural and manual placed rocks for a better transition between terrain and rocks.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Space volumes detection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Professional/SpaceVolumes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Space volumes detection" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Professional/SpaceVolumes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Professional/SpaceVolumes.html"><![CDATA[<p>The sounds team uses volumes to modify the sounds. Making a stone room sound different then a wooden one, etc. These volumes where originally placed by hand trough a clunky interface. The request was to have a tool that could be run on an entity and generate volumes for them.  These did not have to be perfect but the closer the better. This way they only had to check and make small tweaks, speeding up their work.</p>

<p>The algorithm takes the entity and tries to detect the rough interior shapes. afterwards it tries to place the best fitting geometric shape before trying to merge similar shapes into bigger ones.</p>
<ul>
  <li>2 cubes next to each other get fused into one.
Afterwards it detects portals, like windows and doors and places special volumes there.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Space_sections_1.jpg" alt="Volumes" />
– <em>House model</em>
<img src="../assets/images/ubisoft/Space_sections_2.jpg" alt="Mesh" />
– <em>Interior volume results</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Ubisoft Mtl</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="Ubisoft" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Professional" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sounds team uses volumes to modify the sounds. Making a stone room sound different then a wooden one, etc. These volumes where originally placed by hand trough a clunky interface. The request was to have a tool that could be run on an entity and generate volumes for them. These did not have to be perfect but the closer the better. This way they only had to check and make small tweaks, speeding up their work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Web comic reader</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Personal/comicReader.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web comic reader" /><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Personal/comicReader</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Personal/comicReader.html"><![CDATA[<p>A large personal python based project I worked on and off over the years.
While not finished it is a good continues exercise in handling large code projects, experimenting with design philosophies and developing python skills.</p>

<p>The main idea is to be able read comics from all different types comic and manga websites in a single app.
The web crawling uses a custom crawler that uses separate XML files for each source to know how to correctly crawl them. This way if a page layout changes it’s easy to update.
Each XML file has a large list of Regex and Xpaths to find and clean data the correct data.</p>

<p>The main loop and many of the components are working:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Supporting multiple sources for a single comic</li>
  <li>Favourites</li>
  <li>Tracking which chapters are read</li>
  <li>Reading a comic</li>
  <li>Infinite scroll on library, async crawling of new entries</li>
  <li>Multiple screen layouts</li>
  <li>Multiple comic types, left to right, right to left, vertical</li>
</ul>

<p>It uses Python 3.7 and PySide5 together with other libraries for web crawling to XML file handling.
Developed skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>System design</li>
  <li>QT &gt; PtSide</li>
  <li>Python</li>
  <li>Threading and services</li>
  <li>Web crawling</li>
  <li>Regex, XPath and XML</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Maurits Laanbroek</name></author><category term="nonWork" /><category term="Tools" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A large personal python based project I worked on and off over the years. While not finished it is a good continues exercise in handling large code projects, experimenting with design philosophies and developing python skills.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Game Lab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Education/gameLab.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game Lab" /><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Education/gameLab</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Education/gameLab.html"><![CDATA[<p>Game lab was a 2 day a week for 2 blocks cross disciplinary project.
For 2 blocks students work in teams to create their own game</p>

<h2 id="gravity-swing">Gravity Swing</h2>
<p><strong>Year 3</strong>
In Gravity swing the player controls a space ship exploring the galaxy. The goal is to gain speed by using the gravity of planets. Once the player goes fast enough she can enter the wormhole to the next level. Gravity swing is a casual game for Android and Ios tables.
During this project I was the team leader, making sure the team can do their work and the project stays on track.
In between managing I work on ship models, cost calculation for publishing the game and research income possibilities.</p>
<hr />

<h2 id="gentleman-vs-hippies">Gentleman VS Hippies</h2>
<p><strong>Year 2</strong>
This is a multi-player tower offence game made where a player plays as either the Gentleman’s or as the Hippies fighting for dominance. The player builds factories that spawn units at set intervals on one of 3 lanes which the player can choose. The units follow a simple rock, paper, scissor principle. The goal is to destroy the other player’s towers and main building while protecting his own. This is done by changing the lanes units move on and countering the units send by the opponent.</p>

<!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. -->

<div class="embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9J3f-1Ua9J8" width="700" height="400" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
  </iframe>
</div>

<p>On this project I was the art leader and worked on character design, modelling rigging and basic level design. Later in the project I switched to programming implementing features and optimizing performance.
<img src="../assets/images/education/gvsm.jpg" alt="Example wall 1" /></p>
<hr />

<h2 id="grow">Grow</h2>
<p><strong>Year 2</strong>
A Gamelab 3 projects for the Ipad using marmalade. The player has control over how the plant grows above and under the ground. Growing the plant costs resources like sun and water. For normal growth only sun is needed but to pass through obstacles the player needs to collect water.
On this projected I was a programmer working on the path finding, field rendering. Its created using marmalade SDK and programmed in C++.</p>

<!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. -->

<div class="embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uWcNn2ItUUk" width="700" height="400" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
  </iframe>
</div>
<hr />

<h2 id="athenas-quest">Athena’s quest</h2>
<p><strong>Year 1</strong>
Athena’s quest is a flash based point and click adventure game with a cyber punk based theme. The player controls Athena on her quest to find out the mysteries of Utopia. On her journey the player has to solve different puzzles and mini games and make the right choices during conversations.</p>

<p>For this project I created several mini games and the matching art assets. Later in the projects I switched to animation for the cut scene in the game.
<!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. --></p>

<div class="embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vzx-nRGKvbU" width="700" height="400" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
  </iframe>
</div>]]></content><author><name>School and others</name></author><category term="nonWork" /><category term="GameLab" /><category term="Education" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Game lab was a 2 day a week for 2 blocks cross disciplinary project. For 2 blocks students work in teams to create their own game]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some fun with python</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Personal/funWithPython.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some fun with python" /><published>2015-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Personal/funWithPython</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Personal/funWithPython.html"><![CDATA[<p>A simple experiment in controlling node placement and colour.</p>

<!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. -->

<div class="embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LxY6ugl54yU" width="700" height="400" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
  </iframe>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Maurits Laanbroek</name></author><category term="nonWork" /><category term="Fun" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A simple experiment in controlling node placement and colour.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Music driven super formula</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Personal/SuperFormula.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Music driven super formula" /><published>2015-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Personal/SuperFormula</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Personal/SuperFormula.html"><![CDATA[<p>A vex experiment to drive the super formula with music</p>

<!-- Feel free to change the width and height to your desired video size. -->

<div class="embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rW1ew_83vAY" width="700" height="400" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
  </iframe>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Maurits Laanbroek</name></author><category term="nonWork" /><category term="Fun" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A vex experiment to drive the super formula with music]]></summary></entry></feed>